Guide to the Robert M. Palmer papers, 1935-2012.
Palmer, Robert M. papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Robert M. Palmer papers, 1935-2012.
14-20-3775
Robert Palmer 1915-2010.
17.7 cubic ft.
Correspondence, printed material, publications, sound recordings.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
The Palmer papers include music manuscripts, teaching materials, correspondence, clippings, reviews, photographs, sound recordings, and other materials.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Robert M. Palmer was the Given Foundation Professor Emeritus of Music at Cornell University, where he taught composition and music theory for 37 years. He was born in Syracuse in 1915. After basic studies in piano, violin, and theory, he entered the Eastman School of Music in 1934 as a pianist, but soon decided to major in composition under Bernard Rogers and Howard Hanson. During this period, he also studied informally with Quincy Porter, who exerted a formative influence on his style. After completing his bachelor's and master's degrees at Eastman, Palmer took private composition lessons with Roy Harris in 1939 and with Aaron Copland at the opening session of Tanglewood during the summer of 1940. He taught composition, theory, and piano at the University of Kansas at Lawrence, before joining the Cornell faculty in 1943, where he replaced his own teacher, Roy Harris.
At Cornell, Palmer founded the Doctor of Musical Arts program in composition (one of the first such programs in the United States) and guided it to national prominence before his retirement in 1980. Among Palmer's former students are Pulitzer-prize winning composers Steven Stucky and Christopher Rouse, as well as Paul Chihara, Leonard Lehrman, Jack Gallagher, and the late Brian Israel. Palmer held awards and fellowships from the National Academy of Arts and Letters (1946), Guggenheim Foundation (1952 and 1960), Fulbright program (1960), and the National Endowment for the Arts (1980). His music was commissioned by the Columbia Broadcasting System, Koussevitsky Foundation, Minneapolis Orchestra (now the Minnesota Orchestra), Elizabeth Sprague Coolidge, Fromm Foundation, and many others.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The Palmer papers include music manuscripts, teaching materials, correspondence, clippings, reviews, photographs, sound recordings, and other materials. The correspondence contains letters from playwright William Gibson, musicologist Alfred Einstein, pianists John Kirkpatrick and Ramon Salvatore, as well as composers Aaron Copland, Roy Harris, Jack Gallagher, Richard Monaco, Goffredo Petrassi, Vincent Persichetti, Burrill Phillips, Quincy Porter, William Schuman, Elie Siegmeister, and many others.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Palmer, Robert, 1915-2010.; Copland, Aaron, 1900-1990.; Einstein, Alfred, 1880-1952.; Gallagher, Jack, 1947-; Gibson, William, 1914-2008.; Harris, Roy, 1898-1979.; Kirkpatrick, John, 1905-1991.; Monaco, Richard, 1930-1987.; Persichetti, Vincent, 1915-1987.; Petrassi, Goffredo, 1904-2003.; Phillips, Burrill.; Porter, Quincy, 1897-1966.; Salvatore, Ramon.; Schuman, William, 1910-1992.; Siegmeister, Elie, 1909-1991.; Cornell University -- Faculty.; Cornell University. Dept. of Music.
Subjects:
Music -- Instruction and study.; Composers -- 20th century.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Biographical Materials
Series II. Correspondence
Subseries IIa. Personal Correspondence
Subseries IIb. General Correspondence
Series III. Scores
Subseries IIIa. Solo Works
Subseries IIIb. Chamber Music
Subseries IIIc. Chamber Orchestra
Subseries IIId. Orchestra
Subseries IIIe. Vocal
Subseries IIIf. Miscellaneous
Series IV. Programs, Catalogues, and Promotional Materials
Subseries IVa. Concert Programs
Subseries IVb. Program Notes
Series V. Articles and Lectures
Subseries Va. Articles on Palmer
Subseries Vb. Articles on General Topics
Series VI. Teaching Materials
Series VII. Sound Recordings
Subseries VIIa. Analog Audio Tapes
Subseries VIIb. Digital Audio Tapes
Subseries VIIc. Reel-to-reel Audio Tapes
Subseries VIId. CDs
Subseries VIIe. Oral History Interviews
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Biographical Materials
  - Genealogy/Family History (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Photographs (Box 1, Folder 2)
    String Quartet No. 5, Group Portrait- Macdowell Colony 1954, portraits, Tanglewood, negatives
  - Biographical information, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Work lists/performance history (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Eastman School of Music yearbook, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Awards, Commissions, and grants (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Annual report of Palmer's professional activities, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Professional associates- AMC, ACA, ASUC, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - BMI reports, 1974-1986 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - BMI reports, 1968-1983 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - BMI year-end report on all performances, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Financial records for royalties and commissions, 1962, 1977, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Travel documents, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Copyright application, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Retirement documents, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Donation of books/LP's to Cornell Music Department, 1981, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous lists (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous notes (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Address book (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Series II. Correspondence
  - Subseries IIa. Personal correspondence
    - Wedding congratulations, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Palmer's 75th birthday retrospective, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      Program, poster, receipts
    - Christmas letters to family and friends, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Letters from family, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Letters to Alice Palmer, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Subseries IIb. General Correspondence
    - [A], 1954-1988 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - [B], 1945-1985 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - [C], 1967-1976 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Copland, Aaron, 1939-1954 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Cox, Sidney, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - [D], 1953-1988 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Davison, John, 1962-1981 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - [E], 1978-1988 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Einstein, Alfred, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Dengel, Eugene, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - [F], 1952-1965, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - [G], 1943-1985 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Gallagher, Jack, 1973-1983, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Gibson, William, 1943, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - [H], 1964-1990 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Harris, Roy, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Husa, Karel, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - [I], 1961 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Johnston, Ben, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Johnson, Hunter, 1938-1991 (Box 1, Folder 44-45)
    - [K], 1950-1986 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Keller, Homer, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - King, James, 1941-1943 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Kirkpatrick, John, 1939-1945 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Koussevitsky Foundation, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - [L], 1938-1980, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Levin and McGraw, 1975, 1984, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - [M], 1945-1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Milner, Anthony, 1982-1988 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Monaco, Richard, 1962-1968 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - [N], 1943, 1958-1967 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - [O], 1955-1956 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - [P], 1942-1995 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - From Palmer, 1969, 1972, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Petrasso, Goffredo, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Persichetti, Vincent, 1945, 1954, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Phillips, Burrill, 1942-1977 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Piston, Walter, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Porter, Quincy, 1938-1941 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - [R], 1948-1982 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - [S], 1965-1996 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Salvatore, Ramon, 1986-1989 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Schuman, William, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Siegmeister, Elie, 1965-1967, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Stucky, Steven, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - [T], 1951-1983 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - [U], 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - [V], 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - [W], 1940, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Walden String Quartet (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Willey, Jim, 1981, 1990-1992 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - [Z], 1980 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Unidentified correspondents, 1954-1991 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Trumpet Sonata, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Palmer's visit to University of Kentucky, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Palmer's trip to Venezuela, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Palmer's 75th Birthday retrospective, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Commissions: letters, contracts, 1978, 1987, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Address list of US university composers (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Correspondence and press releases regarding 5th String Quartet, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Correspondence and documents regarding CRI recording of 2nd Piano Sonata, 1981-1983 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Correspondence with Southern Music publishers, 1957-1958, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Correspondence with publisher CF Peters, 1953-1980 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Letters from publisher Robert King, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Series III. Scores
  - Subseries IIIa. Solo Works
    - Piano Sonata No. 1: Scores (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Piano Sonata No. 1: Draft of Third Movement (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Piano Sonata No. 2: Sketches (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Piano Sonata No. 2: Scores, 2 copies., 1948 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Piano Sonata No. 3: Sketches (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Piano Sonata No. 3: Manuscript score (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Piano Sonata No. 3: Scores (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Piano Sonata No. 3: Score (print template:unbound), 1979 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Anadolia for piano: Manuscript score and program note (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Interrupted Tango for piano: sketches, manuscript score, articles on tango (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Interrupted Tango for piano: Scores with corrections (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Ballade for piano: Sketches, draft score (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Three Epigrams for piano: Score, ed. John Kirkpatrick (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Three Epigrams for piano: Publisher proof with corrections (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Epigram I-IV for piano: Sketches (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Epigram IV for piano: Manuscript score- vellum (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Epigram I-XI for piano: Sketches and manuscript score (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Epigram V-VIII for piano: Manuscript score (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Epigrams I-IX for piano: Bound score (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Epigram IV-IX for piano: Unbound score (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Epigram VIII-X for piano: Sketches (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Epigram X-XII for piano: Copies and manuscript score (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Epigram XIII-XIV for piano: Sketches (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Three Preludes for piano: Sketches/clean copy (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Three Preludes for piano: Scores. 1 copy of 1947, 2 copies of 1968., 1947, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Prelude IV: Draft score (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Prothalamion for piano: Sketches, draft score, and clean copy (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Transitions for piano: Sketches (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Transitions for piano: Manuscript score (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Transitions for piano: Copyist manuscript (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Transitions for piano: Scores (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Transitions for piano: Score- vellum and paper copy, 1971 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Toccata Ostinato for piano: Sketch (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Toccata Ostinato for piano: Scores, 2 copies., 1945 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Morning Music for piano: Sketches (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Morning Music for piano: Manuscript score (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Morning Music for piano: Published score (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Evening Music for piano: Drafts (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Evening Music for piano: Score- John Kirkpatrick's copy (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Evening Music for piano: Published score (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Reflections for harp: Sketches and draft score- incomplete (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Epithalamium for organ: Draft score (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Epithalamium for organ: Revisions (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Epithalamium for organ: Unbound score (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Subseries IIIb. Chamber Music
    - Sonata for Piano Four-Hands: Sketch (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Sonata for Piano Four-Hands: Sketches and manuscript score (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Sonata for Piano Four-Hands: Score (original transparencies) (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Sonata for Piano Four-Hands: Score (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Sonata for Piano Four-Hands: Published score. 2 copies., 1969 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Sonata for Two Pianos: l only (Score, manuscript sketch book) (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Sonata for Two Pianos: Score: (ed. John Kirkpatrick) (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Sonata for Two Pianos: Score (manuscript) (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Sonata for Two Pianos: Score (unbound, peer ed. with corrections) (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Sonata for Two Pianos: Score (bound, peer ed. with corrections) (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Sonata for Two Pianos: Score (Malcolm Bilson's copy) (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Early Violin Sonata: Manuscript Score, part and draft score of Movement II, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Early Violin Sonata: Sketch, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Early Violin Sonata, Woodwind Quintet, String Quintet: Sketches, 1942, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Violin Sonata: Draft score, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Violin Sonata: Manuscript score on transparencies, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Violin Sonata: Score, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Violin Sonata: Score with corrections, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Violin Sonata: Score (annotated with revisions), 1956 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Violin Sonata: Corrections (inserts), 1956 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Violin Sonata: Addenda/errata, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Violin Sonata: Proofs of score and parts (computer engraving), 1956 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Violin Sonata: Manuscript (early version), 1956 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Violin Sonata: Violin part (annotated), 1956 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Violin Sonata: Violin part (proof for publication, with annotation), 1956 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Violin Sonata: Violin part, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Violin Sonata: Part (manuscript- definitive version print master), 1956 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Violin Sonata: Part, print master manuscript, 1955-1956 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Viola Sonata: Draft score (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Viola Sonata: Manuscript score (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Viola Sonata: scores (unbound proof, 2 bound scores with corrections, performance copy with annotation) (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Viola Sonata: score with corrections (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Cello Sonata No. 1: Sketch (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Cello Sonata No. 1: Sketches (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Cello Sonata No. 1: Sketches (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Cello Sonata No. 1: Sketches (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Cello Sonata No. 1: Score (manuscript) (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Cello Sonata No. 1: Cello part (manuscript) (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Cello Sonata No. 1: Copy of 4 pages from Movement I, with corrections (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Cello Sonata No. 1: Score (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Cello Sonata No. 1: Cello part (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Cello Sonata No. 2: Sketches (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Cello Sonata No. 2: Cello part (manuscript) (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Cello Sonata No. 2: Annotated score (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Cello Sonata No. 2: Score (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Cello Sonata No. 2: Cello part (III, incomplete) rough copy (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Cello Sonata No. 2: Cello part (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Sonata for Clarinet and Piano: Unfinished sketches (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Sonata for Flute and Piano, III: draft scores (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Sonata for Flute and Piano: draft score, unbound copy with corrections, 1991-1992 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Sonata for Flute and Piano: draft score, II movement (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Sonata for Flute and Piano: score manuscript, 1993 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Sonata for Flute and Piano: score, 1993 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Sonata for Flute and Piano: unbound copies of score with corrections (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Sonata for Flute and Piano: scores with revisions (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Sonata for Flute and Piano: flute part (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Sonata for Flute and Piano: flute part- bound, with performer's notes, 1993 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Sonata for Trumpet and Piano: sketches (early versions) (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Sonata for Trumpet and Piano: Sketches (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Sonata for Trumpet and Piano: Sketches (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Sonata for Trumpet and Piano: Annotated score (I and II only) (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Sonata for Trumpet and Piano: Score (manuscript) (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Sonata for Trumpet and Piano: Trumpet part (manuscript) (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Sonata for Trumpet and Piano: Annotated score (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Sonata for Trumpet and Piano: Score (alternate copy) (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Sonata for Trumpet and Piano: Score (first revision) (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Sonata for Trumpet and Piano: Score (first revision, with pianist annotations) (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Sonata for Trumpet and Piano: Score (Robert King ed.) (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Sonata for Trumpet and Piano: Score (with corrections) (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Sonata for Trumpet and Piano: Score (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Sonata for Trumpet and Piano: Trumpet part (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Sonata for Trumpet and Piano: Program (1994)/sheet on trumpet performance (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Study for Two Violins: Sketch (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Duo for Oboe and Viola (marked "in progress" on original folder): Draft score (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Trio for Violin, Viola and Cello: score manuscript, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - IInd Trio for Violin, Viola and Cello: holograph score, 1942 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - IInd Trio for Violin, Viola and Cello: holograph parts (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - IInd Trio for Violin, Viola and Cello: score with annotations, 1942 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - IInd Trio for Violin, Viola and Cello: score, unbound with letter, 1942 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Trio for Violin, Cello and Piano: draft score, 1957-1958 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Trio for Violin, Cello and Piano: handwritten program notes, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Sketchbook: includes draft of String Quartet and sketches for symphony, 1937-1938 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - String Quartet No. 1: score manuscript, 1939 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - String Quartet No. 1: score, 2 unbound copies (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - String Quartet No. 1: score with markings (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - String Quartet No. 1: parts (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Piano Trio: score- lecture copy with annotations, 1958 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Piano Trio: violin and cello parts, 1958 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - String Quartet No. 2: analytical examples (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - String Quartet No. 2: Sketches, 1940-1948 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - String Quartet No. 2: score- clean copy, ink on paper, incomplete, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - String Quartet No. 2: score- clean copy, ink on vellum, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - String Quartet No. 2: rejected pages with revisions, 1948, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - String Quartet No. 2: IV parts manuscript (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - String Quartet No. 2: parts, ink on vellum, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - String Quartet No. 2: parts- I violin and cello (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - String Quartet No. 2: unbound score with corrections (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - String Quartet No. 2: revision of middle of 1st movement, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - String Quartet No. 2: score of revised version, unbound (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - String Quartet No. 2: revision materials (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - String Quartet No. 2: score of revised version, unbound with materials, 1940-1948 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - String Quartet No. 2: bound scores (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - String Quartet No. 2: parts- complete set, different copies (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - String Quartet No. 2: large scores (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - String Quartet No. 2: incomplete parts (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - String Quartet No. 3: sketch (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - String Quartet No. 3: draft scores manuscript, 1954 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - String Quartet No. 3: miscellaneous loose papers, 1954 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - String Quartet No. 3: score (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - String Quartet No. 3: score with corrections (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - String Quartet No. 3: parts (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - String Quartet No. 4: sketch (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - String Quartet No. 4: sketches (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - String Quartet No. 4: draft score manuscript, 1959 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - String Quartet No. 4: score manuscript, 1959-1960 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - String Quartet No. 4: score (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - String Quartet No. 4: scores with corrections, 1959 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - String Quartet No. 4: score- unbound, original folder marked 'master fully corrected 6/26/96' (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - String Quartet No. 4: scores- newer version has many revisions included (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - String Quartet No. 4: score, revision copy (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - String Quartet No. 4: score, revision copy, 1959-1960 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - String Quartet No. 4: parts (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - String Quartet No. 5: sketch 'pre-copy' (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - String Quartet No. 5: sketches (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - String Quartet No. 5: score manuscript, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - String Quartet No. 5: parts manuscript, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - String Quartet No. 5: unbound score, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - String Quartet No. 5: score, incomplete with markings, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - String Quartet No. 5: scores, annotated with lecture notes (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - String Quartet No. 5: revisions, annotated copies of score (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Piano Quartet No. 1: sketches (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Piano Quartet No. 1: score, clean copy, ink on vellum, 1945-1947 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Piano Quartet No. 1: score (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Piano Quartet No. 1: parts- violin, viola, and cello, multiple copies. (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Piano Quartet No. 2: sketches- abandoned version (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Piano Quartet No. 2: score and sketches- manuscript, pencil, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Piano Quartet No. 2: score- clean copy, pencil on vellum (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Piano Quartet No. 2: unbound scores (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Piano Quartet No. 2: bound scores (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Piano Quartet No. 2: bound parts, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Piano Quartet No. 2: parts, original transparencies, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Organon I for flute, clarinet, violin and cello: sketches, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Organon I Division II (or Organon II): score and sketches manuscript, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Organon I for flute, clarinet, violin and cello: score, pencil manuscript, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Organon I for flute, clarinet, violin and cello: score manuscript (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Organon I for flute, clarinet, violin and cello: manuscript score (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Organon I for flute, clarinet, violin and cello: parts, pencil manuscript (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Organon I for flute, clarinet, violin and cello: parts manuscript (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Organon I for flute, clarinet, violin and cello: scores (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Organon I for flute, clarinet, violin and cello: unbound scores (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Organon I for flute, clarinet, violin and cello: scores, mostly unbound fragments (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Organon I for flute, clarinet, violin and cello: parts (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Piano Quintet: sketches (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Piano Quintet: score, 1953 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Woodwind Quintet: short score/draft score, 1951 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Woodwind Quintet: clean copy- score and parts, ink on vellum, 1951 (Box 16, Folder 4)